

Tomáš Němec

Tomáš is a kind IT technician who is obsessed with the murder of his half sister Emilie, six years ago.

Tomáš Němec is a 24-year-old IT technician whose life is dominated by solving the murder

of his half sister, Emilie Němec. Emilie was stabbed in 2013 and the killer was never brought to justice.

He is Czech. He started studying computing at college but never finished the course. He is allergic to shellfish. He has a severe phobia of water

Physically, Tomáš is in pretty good shape. He is averageheight with light skin, red blond hair and blue eyes. Unusually, he has a prosthetic foot; a shark ate his.

He grew up in a working class neighbourhood. His mother left when he was young, leaving him with his father, who was a drunk.

He is currently single. His most recent romance was with a student called Eliška Musilová, who was the same age as him. They broke up because Eliška couldn't deal with Tomáš's obsession with Emilie's death.

Tomáš's best friend is an IT technician called Roman Svoboda. They are inseparable. He also hangs around with Miroslav Javorský and Soňa Šebková. They enjoy cycling together.

Basic Information

Name:	Tomáš Němec
Nickname:	Lazy Tomáš
Reason for nickname:	Descriptive
Date of birth:	Saturday, 14th Oct 1995 (Age 24)
Star sign:	Libra
Nationality:	Czech
Ethnicity:	Caucasian
Social class:	Working class
Religion:	Agnostic
Sexuality:	Unknown
Education:	Some college
Course:	Computing
Political views:	Centre
Relationship status:	Single
Career path:	Computing

Physical characteristic

Height:	average
Shape:	average
Build:	average
Hair colour:	brown
Eyes:	blue
Glasses/lenses:	none
Prosthetics	prosthetic foot

Personality

Positive characteristics:	kind, careful
Negative characteristics:	lazy, untidy
Words often used:	careful, kind, lazy, untidy
Other words that might be used:	aware, benevolent, benignant, blowsy, careful, cautious, certain, charitable, close, cluttered, conscientious, considerate, deliberate, detailed, disheveled, dishevelled, disorderly, elaborate, elaborated, forgiving, frowsy, frowzy, generous, genial, gentle, good, gracious, heedful, helpful, higgledy-piggledy, hospitable, hugger-mugger, humane, jumbled, kind, kindhearted, lazy, littered, measured, merciful, messy, mindful, minute, mussy, narrow, openhearted, painstaking, particular, provident, rumpled, scraggly, scrupulous, slatternly, sloppy, slouchy, slovenly, sluttish, sprawling, straggly, studious, sure, sympathetic, thorough, thoughtful, thrifty, tolerant, topsy-turvy, tousled, troubled, unhurried, unkempt, untidy
Moral:	sometimes
Stable:	sometimes
Loyal:	sometimes
Generous:	sometimes
Extrovert:	not at all
Compassionate:	very
IQ:	101
Hobbies:	looking for clues, planking, interviewing suspects, cycling, going to the movies, eating out, charity work, escapology, jigsaw puzzles, bowling
Bad habits:	obsessing over Emilie Němec's murder
Phobias:	water
Diet	eats meat
Favourite foods:	blueberry muffins, chocolate biscuits
Allergies and intolerances:	shellfish

Employment

Sales assistant at book store	Luxor	2014 - 2018	resigned
IT technician	Arbes Technologies	2018 - present	

Background

Early years	Tomáš grew up in an impoverished neighbourhood. His mother left when he was young, leaving him with his father, who was a drunk.
Formative years	Tomáš started college but quit part way through the course. Tomáš got is first job as a sales assistant at office supplies store at age 19
Most traumatic childhood experience:	His mother leaving when he was four.

Relationships Friends

Roman Svoboda (Lifespan: 1996 - present)		
Relation	Friend	
Occupation	IT Technician	
Age	23	
Relationship	They are inseparable	

Miroslav Javorský (Lifespan: 2000 - present)		
Relation	Friend	
Occupation Junior manager		

Age	19
Relationship	They get on well most of the time

Soňa Šebková

(Lifespan: 2000 - present)

Relation	Friend	
Occupation	Sous chef	
Age		19
Relationship	They are inseparable	

Parents

Karo	lína	Hái	ikov	νá
IXAIO	IIII	i iu	יטיון	V

(Lifespan: 1972 - present)

Relation	Mother
Occupation	Journalist
Age	47
Relationship	Non-existent.

František Němec

(Lifespan: 1976 - present)

Relation	Father
Occupation	Plumber

Age	43
Relationship	Fractious.

Siblings

Monika Hájková

(Lifespan: 1988 - present)

Relation	Half sister (shared mother)
Occupation	Lab assistant
Age	31
Relationship	Tomáš and Maisie grew up together. Nevertheless, they are not particularly close.

Emilie Němec

(Lifespan: 1991 - 2013)

Relation	Half sister (shared mother)
Occupation	Artist
Age	Died in 2013 aged 22. (Would have been 28.)
Cause of death	murdered - stabbed
Relationship	Tomáš is obsessed with solving Emilie's murder

Matěj Němec

(Lifespan: 1992 - present)

Relation	Half brother (shared father)
Occupation	Lab assistant
Age	27
Relationship	Tomáš and Matěj grew up in separate homes but see each other a lot.

Martin Němec

(Lifespan: 1993 - present)

Relation	Brother	
Occupation	Sales assistant	
Age		26
Relationship	They do not get on well.	

Former Partners

			,	
Sand	Ira	$\mathbf{\nu}_{\mathbf{G}}$	\mathbf{C}	19
Sand	II a	1 13	\mathbf{v}	a

(Lifespan: 1982 - present)

Relation	Ex-girlfriend (4 years : 2011 - 2015)
Occupation	Kitchen assistant

Reason for breakup	Sandra felt Tomáš was so cautious that he was afraid to live
Age	37
Relationship	Occasional frosty contact

Eliška Musilová

(Lifespan: 2002 - present)

Relation	Ex-girlfriend (1 year : 2018 - 2019)
Occupation	Student
Reason for breakup	Eliška couldn't deal with Tomáš's obsession with Emilie's death
Age	17
Relationship	Occasional frosty contact

Political Views

Abortion:	pro
Racial equality:	pro
LGBTQ rights:	very pro
Subsidised healthcare:	pro
Gun control:	undecided
Nuclear disarmament:	very against

Death penalty:	undecided
Tax cuts for the wealthy:	against
Protecting the environment:	undecided

1995	Age 0	Tomáš Němec is born
1999	Age 4	Mother, Karolína Hájková walks out
2011	Age 16	Gets together with Sandra Píšová.
2013	Age 18	Emilie Němec is murdered. Half sister (shared mother), Emilie dies aged 22 (murdered - stabbed)
2014	Age 19	Starts work at Luxor book store as a sales assistant
2015	Age 20	Tomáš is attacked by a shark and loses foot Relationship with Sandra Píšová ends (Sandra felt Tomáš was so cautious that he was afraid to live).
2018	Age 23	Gets together with Eliška Musilová. Resigns from job as a sales assistant at Luxor Starts work at Arbes Technologies at IT technician
2019	Age 24	Relationship with Eliška Musilová ends (Eliška couldn't deal with Tomáš's obsession Emilie's death).
2019- 10-08		Present Day